# **Brendan Dagys**

brendandagys@gmail.com | Website/Portfolio: brendandagys.com | GitHub: github.com/brendandagys

# **Summary**

Passionate and highly-motivated full-stack software engineer. I have professional experience with TypeScript/JavaScript, Python, React, Vue, Django, AWS, Node.js, Rust, and other technologies. I am interested in exciting and challenging opportunities where I can make a positive impact in the lives of others while continuing to add to and refine my skill set.

#### Education

### Ryerson University, Toronto, Ontario

- Data Analytics, Big Data, and Predictive Analytics, Certificate (2018)
- Biomedical Engineering, B. Eng. (2016)

#### Amazon Web Services certifications

- Solutions Architect Professional
- DevOps Engineer Professional
- Certified Security Specialty

# **Work Experience**

Software Developer, Rentsync (March 2022 - Present)

- Improved API response times up to 3x with the development of a Rust GraphQL API microservice using Apollo Federation
- Built a library of automated data integrity checks that decreased data errors by 90% and eliminated hours of investigative work
- · Reduced the quarterly count of bug tickets through the promotion of TypeScript in numerous repositories
- Implemented revenue-generating and cost-/resource-saving features

#### Senior Data and Research Analyst, Michael Garron Hospital (February 2021 - March 2022)

- Created a fully-automated data submission pipeline to send quarterly data to GEMINI, a province-wide big data healthcare initiative
- Eliminated 100% of administrative work for numerous research studies by writing scripts that extracted study data from lab results

### Decision Support and Data Consultant, North Bay Regional Health Centre (July 2018 - February 2021)

- Developed a hospital-wide staff management application used by dozens of managers, that reduced calls to the staffing department by 75% due to the availability of information and automated delivery of status updates
- Created data reports and analyses from multifarious sources, including a 25,000-table relational database, and consulted with senior leaders and other stakeholders

## Data Analyst, North Bay Regional Health Centre (July 2017 - July 2018)

· Collected, cleaned, and analyzed healthcare information system data with high accountability

#### Skills

- <u>Languages</u>: TypeScript/JavaScript, Rust, Python, Pandas, SQL
- Web: React, Redux, Django, Vue 2/3, Next.js, Nuxt, Node.js, Express, Koa, Yew
- AWS: EKS, Lambda, API Gateway, S3, VPC, IAM, EC2, CloudFormation, CodePipeline, CloudWatch, SQS, etc.
- <u>Database systems</u>: PostgreSQL, MySQL, Redis, DynamoDB, MongoDB, Oracle, Aurora, RDS
- Miscellaneous:
  - o Terraform, Kubernetes, Docker, GraphQL and REST APIs
  - o HTML/CSS, Bootstrap, MUI, Tailwind, Jquery
  - o Git, Jira, Linux

# **Projects**

- Serverless vacation rental booking site built on AWS
- Console text editor using the C standard library
- C compiler, written in C
- Staff management tool used by a hospital to manage shift scheduling for hundreds of employees
- Personal finance tracker with Python/Django that tracks spending habits and displays statistics
- UX-focused COVID-19 screening app with MERN stack

### **Additional Skills**

- Agile software development methodology
- · Knowledge of distributed systems
- Strong communication and team-building abilities